chapter 13 of Black Beauty this LibriVox recording is in the public domain Black
Beauty by Anna Su chapter 13 The Devil's Trade Mark One day when John and I had been
out on some business of our masters and were returning gently on a long, straight
road, at some distance we saw a boy trying to leap a pony over a gate; the
pony would not take the leap, and the boy cut him with the whip, but he only turned
off on one side. He whipped him again, but the pony turned off on the other side.
Then the boy got off and gave him a hard thrashing, and knocked him about the head;
then he got up again and tried to make him leap the gate, kicking him all the
time shamefully, but still the pony refused. When we were nearly at the spot
the pony put down his head and threw up his heels, and sent the boy neatly over
into a broad Qui quick set hedge, and with the rain dangling from his head he
set off home at a full gallop JN laughed out quite loud. “Served him right,” he said.
“Oh, oh, oh!” cried the boy as he struggled about among the thorns; “I say, come and
help me out.” “Thank ye,” said JN I think you are
quite in the right place, and maybe a little scratching will teach you not to
leap a pony over a gate that is too high
for him,” and so with that JN rode off. “It may be,” said he to himself, “that young
fellow is a liar as well as a cruel one; we'll just go home by Farmer Busby's
Beauty, and then if anyone wants to know you and I can tell him you
see.” So we turned off to the right, and soon came up to the stackyard and within
sight of the house. The farmer was hurrying out into the road, and his wife
was standing at the gate, looking very frightened. “Have you seen my boy?” said Mr
Busby as we came up; “he went out an hour
ago on my black pony, and the creature is just come back without a
rider.” “I should think, sir,” said John, “he had better be without a rider, unless he
can be ridden properly.” “What do you mean?” said the
farmer. “Well, sir, I saw your son whipping, and kicking, and knocking that good
little pony about shamefully because he would not leap a gate that was too high
for him. The pony behaved well, sir, and showed no vice; but at last he just threw
up his heels and tipped the young gentleman into the thorn hedge. He wanted
me to help him out, but I hope you will
excuse me, sir, I did not feel inclined to do so. There's no bones broken, sir; he'll
only get a few scratches. I love horses, and it rils me to see them badly used; it
is a bad plan to aggravate an animal until he uses his heels; the first time
is not always the last.” During this time the mother began
to cry, “Oh, my poor Bill, I must go and meet him; he must be
hurt.” “You' better go into the house, wife,” said the farmer; “Bill wants a lesson
about this, and I must see that he gets it; this is not the first time, nor the
second, that he has ill used that pony, and I shall stop it I'm much obliged to
you, Manly good evening So he went on, John chuckling all
the way home; then he told James about it, who laughed and said, “Serve him right. I
knew that boy at school; he took great airs on himself because he was a
farmer's son; he used to swagger about and bully the little boys. Of of course,
we elder ones would not have any of that nonsense, and let him know that in the
school and in the playground farmer sons and laborer sons were all
alike. I well remember one day, just before afternoon school, I found him at
the large window catching flies and pulling off their wings. He did not see
me and I gave him a box on the ears that laid him sprawling on the floor. Well,
angry as I was, I was almost frightened, he roared and bellowed in such a style.
The boys rushed him from the playground, and the master ran in from the road to
see who was being murdered. Of course I said fair and square at once what I had
done, and why; then I showed the master the flies, some crushed and some crawling
about helpless, and I showed him the wings on the window sill and never saw
him so angry before; but as Bill was still howling and whining, like the
coward that he was, he did not give him any more punishment of that kind, but set
him up on a stool for the rest of the afternoon, and said that he should not go
out to play for that week.
Then he talked to all the boys very seriously about cruelty, and said how
hard-hearted and cowardly it was to hurt the weak and the helpless; but what stuck
in my mind was this, he said that cruelty was the devil's own trademark and if we
saw anyone who took pleasure in cruelty we might know who he belonged to, for the
devil was a murderer from the beginning, and a tormentor to the end. On the other
hand, where we saw people who love their neighbors, and were kind to man and beast,
we might know that Gods mark.” “Your master never taught you a
truer thing,” said JN there is no religion without love, and people may talk as much
as they like about their religion, but if it does not teach them to be good and
kind to man and beast it is all a sham—
—all a sham, James, and it won't stand when things come to be turned inside
out end of chapter 13